Alchemy is a science where one understands the structure of matter, breaks it down, then rebuilds it.
錬金術は　物質を理解分解再構築する科学なり
However, it is not an all-powerful technique,
as one cannot create something out of nothing.
されど　万能の技にはあらず
無から有を生ずることあたわず
If one wishes to gain something,
one must present something of equal value.
何かを得ようと欲すれば
必ず同等の代価を支払うものなり
This is the concept of equivalent exchange, the fundamental basis of alchemy.
これすなわち錬金術の基本　等価交換なり
However, there is a taboo in alchemy. Human transmutation.
錬金術師に禁忌あり
そは人体錬成なり
One must not commit this act.
これ何人も犯すことなかれ
I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
この想いを　消してしまうには
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
I want to go back and finish
やり残してるコト
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
やり直してみたいから
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
夢のつづき　追いかけていたはずなのに
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
曲がりくねった　細い道　人につまずく
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
あの頃みたいにって　戻りたい訳じゃないの
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
無くしてきた空を　探してる
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
わかってくれますように
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
犠牲になったような　悲しい顔はやめてよ
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
罪の最後は涙じゃないよ
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
ずっと苦しく背負ってくんだ
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
出口見えない感情迷路に
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
誰を待ってるの？
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
白いノートに綴ったように
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
もっと素直に吐き出したいよ
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
何から　逃れたいんだ
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
…現実ってやつ？
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
叶えるために　生きてるんだって
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
叫びたくなるよ　聞こえていますか？
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
無難になんて　やってられないから
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
…帰る場所も無いの
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
優しさには　いつも感謝してる
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
だから強くなりたい(I'm on the the
(I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
懐かしくなる
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
こんな痛みも歓迎じゃん
Konna itami mo kangei jan
To you, children of God, who live on this earth,
この地上に生ける神の子らよ
pray and believe, and you shall be saved.
祈り信じよ　されば救われん
The Sun God Leto shines light upon you to show you the way.
太陽の神レトは
Are you guys street performers or something?
あんたら　大道芸人かなんかかい
Where in the world did you get that idea?
オレたちのどこが大道芸人なんだよ
Am I wrong?
違うのか
Thanks for the meal.
ごちそうさん
Hey now, sir!
おい　ちょっとお客さん
Sorry about that, we'll fix it.
あっ悪ぃ悪ぃ
直すから
"Fix", you say?
直すからって
Well, just watch.
まあ　見てな
Well then, here I go!
そんじゃあ　いきま～す
How's that?
これでいいかな
Now that's quite a surprise.
こりゃ驚いた
You're able to perform miracles, as well?
あんた奇跡の業が使えるのかい
What the heck are you talking about?
なんだいそりゃ
We're alchemists.
僕たち錬金術師ですよ
That's the first time I've seen anything like that.
錬金術ってやつ　初めて見たぜ
You've never heard of us, the Elric Brothers, before?
エルリック兄弟って聞いたことね
"Elric"?
エルリック
Actually, I have.
ああ　聞いたことがある
The Fullmetal Alchemist, Edward Elric!
鋼の錬金術師　エドワード·エルリック
Oh, so you're that rumored genius alchemist.
いや　あんたが噂の天才錬金術師か
Ah, I get it! Your other name is "Fullmetal" because of this suit!
なるほど
こんな鎧着てるから　ふたつ名が鋼なのか
No... You have the wrong person...
あの　僕じゃなくて
Huh? That little guy over there?
えっ　あっちのちっこいの
Who are you calling a pea-sized runt?!
誰が豆粒ドチビかぁ
Pray and believe...
祈り　信じよ
So, what the heck is this broadcast?
で　この放送何
I-It's the High Priest Cornello...
コ　コーネロ教主様だ
He came here a few years ago and preached to us about the path of God.
数年前にこの町に現れて
オレたちに神の道を説いてくださったのだ
"God will grant eternity to the living and resurrection to the dead."
生きる者には永遠を
死せる者には復活を与えてくださる
And proof of it all are the miracles that he produces.
その証拠が奇跡の業さ
"Resurrection to the dead", eh?
死せる者に復活をねぇ
Sounds fishy to me.
うさんくせぇな
That's what they were talking about, huh?
あれか
What do you think?
どう思う
It's pretty obvious from that transmutation response that it's alchemy.
どうもこうも
あの変成反応は錬金術でしょ
But he's totally ignoring the concept of equivalent exchange.
でも等価交換無視してんぞ
It's a rule that you can only produce something from matter of equal value.
質量１のものから質量１のものしか出来ないのは原則だろ
He changed a flower to a mineral, too.
植物を鉱物に変えてるしね
Brother, could it be...
兄さん　ひょっとして
Yeah. It could be...
ああ　ひょっとすると
Bingo.
ビンゴだぜ
God... please listen to my wish...
神様　私の願いをお聞き届けください
Please bring back-
あの人を
Ah, so this is Mr. Leto.
へえ　こいつがレトさんか
Are you interested in the religion of Leto?
レト教に興味がおありですか
Nah. Unfortunately, I'm an atheist.
いや　あいにくと無宗教でね
That's not good.
いけませんねそれは
Believing and honoring God,
and living in gratitude and hope...
神を信じ　敬い
感謝と希望に生きる
How glorious.
なんとすばらしいことでしょう
If you believe...
信ずれば
I'm sure you'll grow taller!
きっとあなたの身長も伸びますよ
What did you say?!
んだよこらぁ
She didn't mean it in a bad way!
悪気はないんだから
"Resurrection to the dead"...
死せる者に復活を
Do you seriously believe something like that?
本気で信じているのか
Yes.
ええ
Water, 35L.
水３５リットル　炭素２０キログラム
Carbon, 20kg.
Ammonia, 4L.
アンモニア４リットル　石灰１.５キログラム
Lime, 1.5kg.
Phosphorus, 800g.
燐８００グラム　塩分２５０グラム
Salt, 250g.
Niter, 100g.
硝石１００グラム　その他もろもろ
And others.
...What?
はあ
Those are the ingredients that make up an average adult human body.
大人１人分として計算した場合の人体構成成分だ
We know this from our advances in science, but there
haven't been any reports of successful human transmutations.
今の科学ではここまで分かってるのに
実際に人体錬成に成功した例は報告されていない
You really think that praying would solve something that even science couldn't solve?
科学でもできないことが
祈ったらできるのかよ
"Pray and believe, and your wishes shall be."
祈り信じよ
さすれば汝が願い成就せり
And by the way,
ちなみに　この成分材料はな
you can buy these basic ingredients at the market with a kid's pocket money.
市場に行けば子供の小遣いでも全部買えちまうぞ
Humans are made pretty cheaply, aren't they?
人間ってのはお安くできてんな
People are not things. Those words are blasphemy to our creator.
人は物じゃありません
そんな言葉　創造主への冒涜です
You'll suffer divine punishment for that.
天罰が下りますよ
Alchemists are scientists, after all.
錬金術師ってのは科学者だからな
We don't believe in creators or the existence of a God.
創造主とか神様とかは信じちゃいないのさ
Looking for the solution to the creation principle of this world and pursuing the truth.
この世の創造原理を解き明かし　真理を追い求める
It's pretty ironic we're the closest things to God
in a sense, even though we have no need for him.
神を必要としていないオレたち科学者が
ある意味神に一番近い所にいるってのは
皮肉なもんだ
Are you saying you're on the same level as God?
ご自分が　神と同列とでも
How arrogant!
傲慢ですね
Arrogant, huh?
傲慢ねぇ
I remember this from a mythical tale.
そういやどっかの神話にあったっけな
"The hero who gets too close to the sun shall have
his wax wings plucked and be dropped to the earth."
太陽に近づきすぎた英雄は
蝋で固めた翼をもがれ　地に落とされるってな
Brother.
兄さん
おっと
Lady, will Mr. Leto save a scientist like me?
Even though I was thinking something like that?
お嬢さん
今みたいなことを考えてた科学者でも
レト様はお救いくださるでしょうか
Of course. He will accept reformers at any time.
もちろんですわ
改心はいつでも受け入れられますよ
High Priest, there are people who wish to have a meeting with you.
教主　面会を求めている者が来ております
Two of them. A child and a man in a suit of armor.
子供と鎧を着た二人組で
They call themselves the "Elric Brothers".
エルリック兄弟と名乗っておりますが
I'm busy. Dismiss them.
私は忙しい　帰ってもらえ
Actually, wait... Did you say... the Elric Brothers?
いや　待て
エルリック兄弟だと
Yes, that's what they said...
はあ　そう名乗っておりましたが
This is going to be trouble.
It's the Fullmetal Alchemist, Edward Elric.
まずいことになった
鋼の錬金術師　エドワード·エルリックだ
The... man in the armor?!
あの鎧男が
Yeah, probably.
ああ　おそらくな
What is a State Alchemist doing here?
国家錬金術師がなぜここに
Could it be that our plan has been...
まさか　我々の計画が
Those dogs of the military must have a good sense of smell.
軍の狗め　よほど鼻がよいとみえる
This way, please.
こちらへどうぞ
The High Priest is a very busy man, and he usually cannot find time for such matters, but...
教主様はお忙しい身で
なかなか時間が取れないのですが
You folks are lucky.
あなた方は運がいい
Sorry for the trouble. I'll try to make it quick.
悪いね　なるべく長話しないようにするからさ
Yeah, let's get this over with as quickly as possible.
そうですね　早く終わらせましょう
Priest, what are you doing?!
副教主様　何をなさるんですか
Rose, these people are heathens who are trying to ensnare the High Priest. They are evil.
ロゼ
この者たちは教主様を陥れようとする異教徒だ　悪なのだよ
No, that's...
そんな
So... let's get this over with quick!
だから　早く終わらせようぜ
Strike!
ストライ～ク
騒がしい
So noisy!
Welcome to the holy order, Fullmetal Alchemist.
神聖なる教団へようこそ
鋼の錬金術師
Sir Cornello!
コーネロ様
Looks like some of us were rather hasty.
先走った連中がいたようだな
I apologize for their rudeness.
失礼の段お詫びしよう
It really doesn't feel like an apology when you're looking down at us from a high place like that.
高い所から見下ろして　詫びもねぇもんだ
Are you here for our dogma?
教義を受けに来たのかね
I have a lot of things I want to learn from you... say,
a method for tricking your followers with petty alchemy.
是非とも教えてもらいたいもんだな
せこい錬金術で信者をだます方法とか
I have no idea what you're talking about.
さてなんのことやら
I can't have you putting my miracles and alchemy on the same level.
私の奇跡の業を錬金術と一緒にされては困る
How's this? Can this be achieved through alchemy?
いかがかな　これが錬金術でなしえると
That's precisely what I'm concerned about.
そこなんだよなぁ
For some strange reason, you can perform
transmutations while clearly ignoring the rules.
法則を無視した錬成がどういうわけかできちゃってるんだよねぇ
Which is why it isn't alchemy-
だから錬金術ではないと
So I was thinking...
そこで思ったんだけど
If you had the legendary amplifier that allows alchemists to perform the impossible, it would be possible in your case.
錬金術師が使えば不可能を可能にするといわれてる
あの伝説の術法増幅器なら
できるんじゃないかなってさ
What?
あの
Yep. Frankly, the Philosopher's Stone. Isn't that what your ring is made of?
そう　ズバリ賢者の石
その指輪がそうじゃねぇのか
That was a long search.
探したぜ
This is just an ordinary ring.
これはただの指輪だ
God has allowed me to perform miracles.
私は神から奇跡の業を許されたのだよ
Still gonna play dumb?
まだとぼけんのか
Guess I'll have to get my hands on you and ask your body for the truth.
どうやらとっ捕まえて　体に聞かなきゃならねぇようだな
You seem to be an incorrigible heathen.
君は度し難い異教徒のようだね
Rose.
ロゼ
Y-Yes?
は　はい
Pick up that pistol.
そこに落ちている銃を拾いなさい
はっ　はい
Yes, sir...
Now shoot the Fullmetal Alchemist.
それで鋼の錬金術師を撃つのだ
I... can't do that...
そんな　できません
My words are God's words.
私の言葉は神の御言葉
This is God's will.
これは神のご意志なのだ
Rose, shoot him.
ロゼ　撃ちなさい
What's wrong?
どうしたんだね
Who was the one...
去年恋人を事故で亡くし
...who rescued you from your despair
after you lost your love in an accident last year?
失意のどん底にいたのを救ったのは　誰だ
It was you, Sir Cornello...
コーネロ様です
That's right. It was I who rescued you.
そうだ　私がお前を救ってやった
And what did I promise you?
そして何を約束した
That you'd revive him!
あの人を生き返らせてくれると
Umm... I'm not the one you're supposed to be aiming at...
ああ　えっと　僕は違うんですけど
I'm the Fullmetal Alchemist, got it?!
オレが鋼の錬金術師だっつーの
Wait, you're the one?!
貴様がそうだったのか
Sorry... I have to.
ごめんね　私にはこうするしかないの
He's a swindler.
あいつはペテン師だぞ
No, he isn't!
違う
He's going to revive him with his miracles!
コーネロ様は　奇跡の業であの人をよみがえらせてくれるわ
Then shoot me.
じゃあ　撃てよ
Al!
アル
Good work. God is rejoicing.
それでいい　神はお喜びだよ
Now, shoot the other.
さあ　残りの一人も撃つのだ
Man, you make your followers do terrible things.
信者にひどいことさせるなぁ
What?!
何っ
What's going on?!
ど　どうなってるの
As you can see...
どうもこうも
...this is how it is.
こういうことで
An empty suit of armor!
中身のない鎧
This, itself, is evidence of their evil!
これこそ連中の邪悪さを証明するものだ
They must be eliminated!
排除すべき存在なのだ
Is this your first time seeing a chimera?
合成獣を見るのは　初めてかね
So you made something like this with your Philosopher's Stone, too, eh?
賢者の石を使ってこんなものまでつくりやがったのか
I should probably arm myself...
こりゃあ　丸腰はきつそうだな
Without a transmutation circle?!
錬成陣なしに
I guess your title of "State Alchemist" has to come with something!
国家錬金術師の名は伊達ではないということか
But...
だが
How do you like those claws that cut through iron?!
どうだ　鉄を切断するツメの味は
Just kidding.
なんちってね
Unfortunately, my leg is a bit special.
あいにくと特別製でね
Bite him to death!
かみ殺せ
What's wrong, stupid cat?
どうした　猫野郎
Get a good taste of it!
しっかり味わえよ
That arm...
あぁ　その腕
...and a brother without his body...
鎧だけの弟
Ah, I see now.
そうかそういうことか
Fullmetal Alchemist... you...
鋼の錬金術師
貴様　やらかしおったな
You've done it, haven't you?!
Get down here, third-rate!
下りてこいよど三流
I'll show you the difference in our skill!
格の違いってやつを見せてやる
Get down here, third-rate!
下りてこいよ　ど三流
格の違いってやつを見せてやる
I'll show you the difference in our skill!
Rose, these guys have committed the greatest taboo alchemists can commit.
ロゼ　この者たちはな
錬金術師最大の禁忌　人体錬成を行ったのだ
Human transmutation.
死んだ人間をよみがえらせようとしたのだよ
They tried to revive the dead.
太陽に近づきすぎた英雄は
"The hero who gets too close to the sun shall have
his wax wings plucked and be dropped to the earth."
翼をもがれて地に落とされる
そんな
No way...
これが神様とやらの領域を侵した咎人の姿さ
This is the body of a sinner who encroached upon God's territory.
ロゼ　こうなる覚悟があるのか
Rose, are you really prepared to be like this?
Edward Elric.
エドワード·エルリック
貴様それで国家錬金術師とはな
And you call yourself a State Alchemist? You make me laugh.
笑わせる
Shut the hell up!
うっせんだよ
賢者の石がなきゃなんにもできねぇどさんぴんが
You can't do anything without
the Philosopher's Stone, third-rate!
High Priest, please give us the stone before you get hurt.
教主さん　痛い目見ないうちに石を僕たちに渡してほしい
How ridiculous! Fools who stepped into God's territory!
笑止　神の領域に踏み込んだ愚か者どもめ
今度こそ　神のもとへ送り届けてやろう
I'll send you to his side, once and for all!
いや　オレって神様に嫌われてるだろうからさ
Nah, God seems to hate me,
so he'll probably send me back even if I went.
行っても追い返されると思うぜ
Al!
アル
何をしておる　追え
What are you doing?! After them!
They are heathens who bring evil to the order! Catch them!
教団にあだなす異教徒だ
捕まえろ
Stop right there!
止まれ
ほら坊主　丸腰でどうする気だ
What do you think you can do unarmed, kid?
ケガしないうちに　おとなしく捕まりな
Just give up before you get hurt.
子供だからって油断するな
Don't let your guard down just because he's a kid!
Out of the way!
はい　邪魔
はいはいはいはい
分かっただろう　ロゼ
Get it now, Rose?
Cornello shot at us, even though you were with us.
コーネロは君がいたのに撃ってきた
あれは　あなたたちが
But that's because you two...
さっきの話　本当なの
Is that story true?
僕たちはただ
We just wanted to see Mom's smiling face again.
もう一度母さんの笑顔が見たかっただけなんだ
でも錬成は失敗した
But the transmutation failed.
It didn't even look human.
人の形をしていなかった
僕たちは間違いを思い知らされた
We learned our mistake the hard way.
人はよみがえらない
People cannot be revived... even our mom.
母さんも
ウソよ　だって
That's not true... because...
錬金術の基本は等価交換だ
The fundamental basis of alchemy is the concept of equivalent exchange.
人体錬成の代償は大きかった
The price we paid for the human transmutation was huge.
兄さんは左足を
Brother lost his left leg, and I lost my body.
僕は体を持っていかれたんだ
見える　兄さんが自分の血で描いたんだ
Can you see it?
Brother drew it with his blood.
It must have been painful for him,
after having his left leg taken away.
左足を持っていかれ　痛かったはずだ
でも兄さんは僕の魂を
But Brother affixed my soul to this suit and gave up his right arm as compensation.
自分の右腕と引き換えに錬成して
鎧に定着させてくれた
僕は兄さんの体を元に戻したいんだ
I want to fix my brother's body.
兄さんも僕を元に戻したいと思っている
Brother wants to get my body back, too.
その結果　命を落とすことになるかもしれない
But we may die trying.
僕たちが選んだのは　そういう業の道だ
That's the path we've chosen.
でも　コーネロ様なら
But, Sir Cornello could...
ロゼ
Rose...
あなたたちにできなくても
Even if you two can't, he could...
コーネロ様ならそれができるのよ
He could do it! He will!
できるのよ
You brat! You'd better be prepared!
小僧　覚悟しろ
Old man, let's have a heart-to-heart talk.
おっさん　腹割って話そうぜ
オレはその石の秘密が知りたいだけだ
I just want to know the secret behind that stone.
それとも軍に出動を要請しようか
Or should I call for the army to mobilize?
石を調べるためにさ
To inspect the stone, that is.
いいだろう
Fine.
What do you plan to do with the Philosopher's Stone?
賢者の石で何しようってんだ
それがあればちんけな教団なんかいらないだろ
You don't need that pitiful order if you have the stone, do you?
教団は私のためなら
The order will produce followers that will joyfully give up their lives for me!
喜んで命も捨てる信者を生み出してくれる
They would be an undefeatable army that does not fear even death.
死をも恐れぬ最強の軍団だ
見ているがいい
Just watch.
あと数年の後に
I'm going to be stripping this country away in a few years.
私はこの国を切り取りに掛かるぞ
賢者の石とバカ信者どもを使ってな
By using the Philosopher's Stone and my stupid followers!
貴様にもそのおこぼれぐらいは分けてやろう
I guess I could share some of the leftovers with you.
何がおかしい
What's so funny?!
This is why I called you third-rate.
だから　あんたは三流だっつんだよ
まっ　まさか
Y...
You didn't...
There are no such things as miracles.
奇跡の業なんてないんだ
みんな賢者の石の力だよ
They were all thanks to the power of the Philosopher's Stone.
Y-You...
き　貴様
When did you flip on that switch?!
いつからだ　そのスイッチ
When?!
いつから
From the very beginning.
最初っから
It's all been leaked, now.
もう全部だだ漏れ
What have you done?!
なんてことを
You brat!!!
このガキ
Too slow!
遅ぇよ
Told ya. We're on totally different levels.
言っただろ
格が違うってよ
私は無敵だ
I'm invincible!
R-Rebound!
リ　リバウンドだ
I'm not giving up yet!
まっ　まだあきらめんぞ
私は　私は　神の代理人だ
I'm... I'm...
God's hand!!!
私の言葉は神の言葉
My words are God's words. This fist is God's fist!
この拳は　神の拳
何が神の拳だ
"God's fist", you say?!
If you like it so much, I'll let you have a taste of it!
そんなに好きならくれてやる
痛ぁ　　うっさい
Shut up!
賢者の石見せろ
Now give me the Philosopher's Stone!
It... broke? What does this mean?
壊れた　どういうことだ
完全な物質であるはずの賢者の石がなぜ壊れる
How could the Philosopher's Stone break? It's supposed to be a perfect substance!
I... I don't know!
しっ知らん　私は何も聞いていない
I didn't hear about this!
たたたっ助けてくれ
P-P-P-Please don't hurt me!
お願いだ　私が悪かった
Please! I was wrong!
So it was a fake?
偽物かよ
I can't do anything without the stone! Please, have mercy!!!
石がないと私は何もできん
助けてくれ
ここまで来て　やっと戻れると思ったのに
I finally thought we'd be able to get our bodies back, and it's...
...fake...
偽物
あ　あの　わっ私は
U-Umm, what about me?
どこへでも好きな所に行きやがれ
Go wherever you want!!!
Yes, sir!
はい
賢者の石は
What about the Philosopher's Stone?
とんだパチもんだった
It was a fake.
そう
I see...
やっとお前の体を元に戻せると思ったのにな
And I thought we'd finally be able to get your body back...
賢者の石を渡して
Give me the Philosopher's Stone!
Rose...
ロゼ
言っただろ　とんだパチもんだって
Didn't I just say that it was a fake?
それに勝手に壊れちまった
And in any case, it broke on its own.
ウソよ　独り占めする気なんでしょ
That's a lie!
You're planning to keep it for yourselves, aren't you!
あなたたちの体
To fix your bodies... right?!
そうよ　それにお母さんだってもう一度
And you want to meet your mother again, too...
Shut up!
黙れ
死んだ人間は生き返らない
The dead cannot be revived...
二度と
Never...
Never.
二度と
But he said that he'd be able to bring him back...
生き返るって言ったのよ
祈ればかなうって言ったのよ
He said that if I prayed, it would come true.
奇跡は起きるって
That a miracle would occur...
What am I supposed to cling to from now on?!
これから私は何にすがって生きていけばいいのよ
教えてよ
Tell me!
Hey...
ねえ
そんなこと　自分で考えろ
Decide that for yourself.
立って歩け　前へ進め
Get up and take a step. Walk forward.
あんたには立派な足がついてるじゃないか
You've got two fine legs on you.
なんにもすがる必要なんてない
You don't need to cling to anything.
どうなってるんだよ
What's going on?!
Let us see the High Priest!
教主を出せぇ
オレたちをだましていたのか
Were you guys tricking us?!
Open this door!!!
開けろ
My plans... ruined by a brat like that...
あんな小僧に私の野望を
ほんと　台なしだわ
Seriously. What a mess.
All you had to do was to wreak a bit of havoc.
ちょっと混乱を起こすだけでよかったのに
貴様
You...
ねえ　ラスト
Hey, Lust?
このおっさん食べていい
Can I eat this guy?
No, Gluttony.
ダメよ　グラトニー
If you eat something like that, you'll get a stomachache.
こんなの食べたらおなか壊すわ
How dare... How dare you all make fun of me!
どいつもこいつもバカにしおって
You're not needed anymore.
あなた　もう用済み
It was just starting to liven up, too.
せっかく盛り上がったのに
また一からやり直しね
I guess we have to start over.
お父様に怒られちゃうわ
Father will get mad at us.
さて　次はどんな手を使おうかしら
Now, I wonder what we should do next...
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
ねえ　君は覚えていますか
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
約束　契り　初夏の風が包む
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
二人　寄り添った
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
無理な笑顔の裏
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
伸びた影をかくまう
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
だから　気づかぬふり　再生を選ぶ
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
テーブルの上の　震えない知らせ　待ち続けて
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
空白の夜も　来るはずのない朝も
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
全部わかってたんだ
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
ねえ　 いつか思い出すでしょう
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
果たせなかった　約束を抱いて
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
二人　歩き出す
Futari arukidasu
日本语字幕录入：FAYFAY
リオールでの一件を報告するため
Ed and Al visit East City, home of Eastern Headquarters, to report the incident in Lior.
東方司令部のある街
漫游字幕组
http://popgo.net/bbs
イーストシティーを訪れたエドとアルは
綴命の錬金術師ショウ·タッカーと彼の娘ニーナに出会う
And they meet Shou Tucker,
the Sewing-Life Alchemist, and his daughter, Nina.
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第４話　錬金術師の苦悩
Episode 4, An Alchemist's Anguish.
出会い　それは苦しみの始まりか
An encounter. Is that the beginning of suffering?